Guide to the Julius Hemphill Papers MSS.542
Fales Library and Special Collections
- The World Sax Quartet - Reel 3 of 4, 1981-1995; cuid20737 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 107)
  Hopkins Center, Dartmough College; May 5, 1981 Recorder: SC-280 Stereo, Halftrack, 7 1/2 IPS Scotch RB-1/4-7 [On reel: ""II""] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- The World Sax Quartet - Reel 4 of 4, 1981-1995; cuid20738 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 108)
  Hopkins Center, Dartmough College; May 5, 1981 Recorder: SC-280 Stereo, Halftrack, 7 1/2 IPS Scotch RB-1/4-7 [On reel: ""III""] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Julius Hemphill 12 pc. Orch, 1980-1995; cuid20739 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 109)
  Live at Public Theatre, Nov 1 / 80 S[ide]-1 ""C"" (Those Blues); Lady S; For Billie; Hard Blues; At Harmony S[ide]-2 Border Town; Open Air; What I Know Now; Dogon A.D. Julius Hemphill, Baikida, Carroll, Henry Threadgill, Stan Strickland, Marty Ehrlich, John Clark, John Purcell, Charles Stevens, Emitt Mcdonald, Warren Smith, Pheeroan Ak Laff, Ed Schuller 7 1/2 IPS Maxell UD XL 35-90B 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Julius Hemphill Quintet sans Julius Hemphill (2nd Set), 1978-1995; cuid20740 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 110)
  5/29/78 CCPH Master Halftrack, 7 1/2 IPS 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Julius Hemphill Quintetv- Reel 1 [of 3], 1978-1995; cuid20741 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 111)
  Sun 5/28/78; Mon 5/29/78 2 track, 7 1/2 IPS Ampex 407 Bruce Bidlack, engineer [Information on sheet insert from B and B Enterprises] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Julius Hemphill Quintet - Reel 2 [of 3], 1978-1995; cuid20742 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 112)
  Sun 5/28/78; Mon 5/29/78 2 track, 7 1/2 IPS Ampex 407 Bruce Bidlack, engineer [Information on sheet insert in audio reel AR-111] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Julius Hemphill Quintet - Reel 3 [of 3], 1978-1995; cuid20743 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 113)
- Soundscape, 1981-1995; cuid20744 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 114)
  12/5/81 Reel #1 of Julius Hemphill - 12/5/81: with; Ray Anderson on tuba and trombone; Bruce Purse on trumpet; john Purcell on saxophones; Marty Ehrlich on sax and flute; and Janet Gryce on bassoon. 7 1/2 IPS Maxell UD XL 50-120B 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- "Bells" with Malinké Elliot, 1976-1995; cuid20745 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 115)
  4 tracks; Scotch B-10 1/2 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Lake Murry Boyé Bluiett - Side #1 Complete, 1977-1995; cuid20746 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 116)
  St. Louis Concert; Recorded: 4/23/77 May 17, 1977 Sax Quartet Tunes: New Orleans Kids: Shu-full; 2 times part II (4 flutes); Brooklyn, Ill. Stereo, Halftrack, 15 IPS Maxell UD 50-120 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- Lake Murry Boyé Bluiett - Side #2 Complete, 1977-1995; cuid20747 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 117)
  St. Louis Concert; Recorded: 4/23/77 May 18/77 Sax Quartet Selections: A. Big Foot; B. Hearts Stereo, Halftrack, 15 IPS Maxell UD 50-120 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- "Bells" / "Ralph Ellison's Long Tongue", 1976-1995; cuid20748 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 118)
  Scotch B-10 1/2 1/4-inch Audio Reel; 4 tracks: Tracks 1, 3: "Bells"; Tracks 2, 4: "Ralph Ellison's Long Tongue."
- "Bells", 1976-1995; cuid20749 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 119)
  7 1/2 IPS TDK Audua L-3600M 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- WSQ, 1977-1995; cuid20750 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 120)
  Moers '77 Sound-Engenieur: H. Schlosser Scotch 262 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- World Sax Quartet, 1982-1995; cuid20751 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 121)
  NPR; 6-29-82 Reel #3 2 tracks, 7 1/2 IPS Ampex 406 1/4-inch Audio Reel
  Preservation Note: Substantial print-through in places, especially at head. Begins with audio only on right channel.
- Twilight Boogie Video, 1976-1995; cuid20752 (Box 8, Video 122)
  Transfer from Open Reel 30 minutes Sony V1-K High Band Master Tape 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- WSQ ""Sun. Nite"", 1989-1995; cuid20753 (Box 9, Vhs 123)
  TV NBC; 3/05/89 Maxell HGS Gold 120 VHS videoassette
- Doxology Documentation, 1994-1995; cuid20754 (Box 9, Vhs 124)
  Col/College; 5/94 Scotch Hi-Fi/T-120 VHS videoassette
- Doxology Video, 1976-1995; cuid20755 (Box 9, Vhs 125)
  Scotch Hi-Fi/T-120 VHS videoassette
- Willisau Switzerland Festival, 1982-1995; cuid20756 (Box 9, Vhs 126)
  8/28-29/82 TDK HS VHS videoassette
- [No title], 1976-1995; cuid20757 (Box 9, Item 127)
  [No shell - Possible taping of transmission from Public TV] VHS videocassette
- Jazz Dancing, 1976-1995; cuid20758 (Box 9, Item 128)
  DVD
- Julius Hemphill Willisau, 1992-1995; cuid20759 (Box 9, Item 129)
  Julius Hemphill Willisau Aug. 28-29, 1992 DVD
- Julius Hemphill Long Tongues, 1990-1995; cuid20760 (Box 9, Item 130)
  Julius Hemphill Long Tongues Dec. 7, 1990 DVD
- Julius Hemphill Ralph Ellison's Long Tongue, 1981-1995; cuid20761 (Box 9, Item 131)
  Julius Hemphill Ralph Ellison's Long Tongue Jan. 2, 1981 DVD
  Duration: 96 minutes.
- John Hicks Quartet, 1976-1995; cuid20762 (Box 9, Item 132)
  John Hicks Quartet The Session DVD
- Hemphill Water Music, 1976-1995; cuid20763 (Box 9, Item 133)
  Hemphill Water Music ... 7/17/76 Environ Perf Environ Performance of Water Music for Woodwinds July 17, 1976 Hemphill; Hamiet Bluiett; Charles Tyler; David Murray; Oliver Lake; Chico Freeman; John Scott A. Mr Neptune; B. Ms Catherine; C. Kinspawn; C. Backwater *Not all sections are indexed on this CD CD
- Hemphill ""Water Music for WW."", 1977-1995; cuid20764 (Box 9, Item 134)
  Hemphill ""Water Music for WW."" Wollman Aud. Columbia U October 3, 1977 performance @ Columbia University Julius Hemphill Water Music for Woodwinds David Murray; Hamiet Bluiett; Charles Tyler; Dewey Redman; Oliver Lake; Julius Hemphill [Note on insert:] Rather erratic recording: level jumps irregularly 3 program #s on this CD: Rather arbitrarily placed - they do not fall squarely on section changes 1 - Mvmt II 00-19:50 2 - Mvmt III CD
- Julius Hemphill Feb. 16, 1987, 1987-1995; cuid20765 (Box 9, Item 135)
  Julius Hemphill Feb. 16, 1987 CD
- Full Coat 16 magnetic sound – Julius Hemphill solo woodwinds
- Camera Original-B Wind
- Camera Original- B Wind – 4 figures in robes
- Camera Original-B Wind - Rat Lecture
- Ectachrome B- reversal- Camera Original
- Full coat 16 magnetic sound
- Full coat 16 magnetic sound
- Ampex sound reel from Sweet Willie Rollbar's Orientation
- A Wind, Reversal Print, Reel I
- A Wind, Reversal Print, Reel II